Continuing Education Photograph Collection
Continuing Education Photograph Collection
1928-1983
1950s
Alexander N. Charters Library of Resources for Educators of Adults
4.5 linear ft.
Records consist of photographs and slides. Organizations represented in the collection include the Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA), the Fund for Adult Education (FAE), the National University Extension Association (NUEA), and Syracuse University. There are also portraits of important people in adult education such as Lyman Bryson, Alexander N. Charters, and A.A. Liveright.
149427
Biographical History
The photographs and slides in the collection have been gathered from a number of individuals and organizations in the field of adult education.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The photographs and slides in this collection have been collected from a number of individuals and organizations. Much of the material dates from the decade of the 1950s, best represented by the photographs pertaining to the programs of the Fund for Adult Education (FAE), coincidentally the largest single group of materials.
Arrangement of the Collection
The materials are arranged alphabetically by organization. A number of portraits are arranged alphabetically within the "Portraits" series.
A group of unidentified photographs follows the alphabetical sequence and, due to format, "Slides" follow the photographs. A folder of printed materials is at the end of the collection. The contents of these are not separately listed, since SEE and SEE ALSO references to them are present in the inventory.
Related Material
The library holds a considerable number of collections related to adult and continuing education. Please refer to for a complete listing.
In particular, see also the following:
Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA) Records
Fund for Adult Education (FAE)
National University Extension Association (NUEA)
Alexander N. Charters Papers
A.A. Liveright Papers
Subject and Genre Headings
Adult education; Bryson, Lyman; Charters, Alexander N.; Liveright, A. A. (Alexander Albert), 1907-; Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults; Fund for Adult Education (U.S.); National University Extension Association; Syracuse University; University Council on Education for Public Responsibility; Adult education; Educators, United States; Photographs.; Slides (photographs); Adult education teachers.; Educators.; Teachers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of various individuals and organizations over more than ten years
Inventory
- Photographs
  - Adult Education Association of the United States (AEA)
    - Annual conference, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Rural discussion groups, Bismark, N.D., 1959 (Box 1)
    - Survey, 1953 (Box 1)
  - American Foundation for Political Education
    - Discussion groups, 1958 (Box 1)
    - Executives' seminar, 1959 (Box 1)
  - American Labor Education Service
    - Leadership training, St. Louis, Mo., 1952 (Box 1)
    - School on World Affairs, New York, undated (Box 1)
  - American Library Association
    - Midwinter Conference, Chicago, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC)
    - New Orleans Meeting, undated (Box 1)
    - Regional Meeting, R.I.T., 1968; See Slides: AUEC Regional Meeting, R.I.T.
  - Association of University Summer Sessions
    - Annual Meeting, Albuquerque, N.M., Oct 1968 (Box 1)
  - California, University of, at Los Angeles (UCLA)
    - University Extension, Liberal Arts, 1959 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Association for Adult Education
    - [general], undated (Box 1)
    - Discussion program, 1956 (Box 1)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA)
    - Board members, Chicago, undated (Box 1)
    - Board members, Chicago (oversize), undated (Oversize 1)
    - Educational facilities, See Slides: CSLEA Educational Facilities
    - Headquarters - Sara Schaffner House, Chicago, 1963 (Box 1)
    - Headquarters - Sara Schaffner House, Chicago (oversize), 1963 (Oversize 1)
    - Leadership seminar, 1953 (Box 1)
    - Memorabilia - news clips, photographs (oversize), 1959-1960 (Oversize 1)
    - Publications, discussion groups, 1954 (Box 1)
    - Staff, undated (Box 1)
    - Staff - Clearinghouse and publications, undated (Box 1)
    - Staff - Clearinghouse and publications (oversize), undated (Oversize 1)
    - [unidentified] (Box 1)
  - Chicago, University of
    - Alumni reunion, 1957 (Box 1)
    - Seminar groups, 1954 (Box 1)
  - College de Pont-Levoy
    - Interiors, exteriors, undated (Box 1)
  - College in the Country
    - Activities (various states), 1955-1956 (Box 1)
    - Delbert Clarke Award (Box 1)
  - Columbia University
    - Arden House, undated (Box 1)
  - Community Leadership Institute, Chattanooga, Tenn.
    - [general], undated (Box 1)
  - Cornell University / Syracuse University Adult Education Gathering, Syracuse, N.Y.
    - [general], 1972 (Box 2)
  - Council of National Organizations
    - Executive Committee, 1953 (Box 2)
    - Television Workshop, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica Films
    - Audiovisual techniques in education, Jan 1964 (Box 2)
  - English Language Institute, Tenn., undated (Box 1)
  - Film Council of America
    - Appointment of President, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Christmas party for staff, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Foreign Policy Association
    - [general], 1955 (Box 2)
  - Freedom Foundation
    - Award, Sioux City, Iowa, undated (Box 2)
  - Fund for Adult Education (FAE)
    - Annual report photographs, undated (Box 2)
    - Annual report photographs, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
    - Annual report photographs, 1955-57 (Oversize 1)
    - Bigwin Conference, 1954; 5 folders (Box 2)
    - Bigwin Conference negatives, 1954?; 1 folder of 3 (Box 2)
    - Bigwin Conference negatives, 1954?; 2 folders of 3 (Box 3)
    - Board of Directors
      - Meeting, 1951 (Box 3)
      - Meeting, 1954; 5 folders (Box 3)
    - Business Executives Leadership Seminar, Pomona College, 1958 (Box 3)
    - Community Leadership Conference
      - Estes Park, Colo., 1957 (Box 3)
      - Washington University, Wildwood Springs Resort, Steelville, Mo. (Box 4)
    - Community Leadership Institute, Rancho Santa Fe, N.M., undated (Box 4)
    - Community Leadership Meeting, Colo., 1952 (Box 4)
    - Conference for Executive Leadership, Memphis, Tenn., 1955 (Box 4)
    - Conferences: Chapel Hill, N.C. and Ardsley-on-Hudson, N.Y., 1957 (Box 4)
    - Denver Fact-finding Survey, 1952 (Box 4)
    - Discussion groups, undated; 4 folders (Box 4)
    - Discussion groups, 1955; 3 folders (Box 4)
    - Discussion program - senior citizens, undated (Box 4)
    - Fellowship Selection Committee, undated (Box 4)
    - FAE Building, White Plains, N.Y., 1957 (Box 5)
    - Interns, undated (Box 5)
    - Little Rock, Ark., Study-Discussion groups, 1955; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Mass media
      - CBS, undated (Box 5)
      - National Selection Committee and grantees, 1958-1959; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Open House, undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Participative art study, undated; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Publications, 1952; 1954 (Box 5)
    - "Shape of our Cities" - Urbanism Discussion Group, Fall, New York?, 1957 (Box 5)
    - Staff, 1955; 3 folders (Box 5)
    - Test Cities
      - Akron, Ohio, 1954; 1957 (Box 6)
      - Bridgeport, University of, Conn., undated (Box 6)
      - California, University of, at Los Angeles, undated (Box 6)
      - Chattanooga, Tenn., undated (Box 6)
      - Chicago Conference, 1953 (Box 6)
      - Colorado Conference, 1952 (Box 6)
      - Kansas City, Mo.
        - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 6)
        - Coordinators' Meeting, 1954 (Box 6)
      - Little Rock, Ark., undated (Box 6)
      - Louisville, Ky., undated (Box 6)
      - Memphis, Tenn., undated (Box 6)
      - Niagara Falls, N.Y., 1953; undated (Box 6)
      - Racine, Wis., undated (Box 6)
      - Rancho Santa Fe Conference, undated (Box 6)
      - Saint Paul, Minn., undated (Box 6)
      - Salt Lake City, Utah, undated (Box 6)
      - San Bernardino, Cal., undated; 1 folder of 3 (Box 6)
      - San Bernardino, Cal., undated; 2 folders of 3 (Box 7)
      - Sioux City, Iowa, ca. 1956 (Box 7)
      - West Texas, undated (Box 7)
      - Whittier, Cal., undated (Box 7)
      - York, Pa., undated (Box 7)
      - Unidentified contact sheets (Box 7)
  - Galaxy Conference
    - Wingspread Conference, Pre-Galaxy, Nov 1969 (Box 7)
      See also Wingspread Conference
  - Georgia, University of
    - Continuing Education Center, undated (Box 7)
  - Great Books Foundation
    - Discussion groups, 1956 (Box 7)
  - IBM
    - Executive program, Poughkeepsie, N.Y., Feb 1965 (Box 7)
  - Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged, Fall 1975, See Slides: Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged, Fall 1975
  - International Congress of University Adult Educators (ICUAE)
    - Conference, 1960 (Box 7)
  - International Council for Adult Education (ICAE)
    - Ottawa, University of, 26-27 May 1975 (Box 7)
  - International Seminar of Adult Education
    - Pinebrook Conference Center, 2-5 Sep 1970 (Box 7)
  - Inter-University Labor Education Committee, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Michigan State University
    - Cooperative Extension Services Project, 1959 (Box 7)
  - National Association of Public School Adult Educators (NAPSAE), undated (Box 8)
  - National Education Association, Division of Adult Education Services, undated (Box 8)
  - National University Extension Association (NUEA)
    - Louisiana State University Caribbean Program, 1952 (Box 8)
    - Meeting, 1966 (Box 8)
    - National Meeting, Miami Beach, 1968, See Slides: NUEA National Meeting, Miami Beach, 1968
    - Region II Meeting, Sagamore, N.Y., undated (Box 8)
    - Seventeenth Annual Conference, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, Minn., May 1932 (Map-case 108)
    - Training Field Workers, undated (Box 8)
    - University of Michigan Extension Services, ca. 1951 (Box 8)
    - University of Michigan Extension Services, oversize photo (Map-case 108)
    - University of Wisconsin, ca. 1950 (Box 8)
  - New York State Education Department, Division of Continuing Education
    - I [LOVE] NY Innovations in Continuing Education, July 1, 1978 - Jun 30, 1979 (Box 8)
  - New York State External High School Diploma Program
    - Long Island Center, undated (Box 8)
  - New York State Public School Adult Educators Association (NAPSAE)
    - Sagamore, N.Y., May 1969 (Box 8)
  - New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
    - Pre-Retirement Preparation Program, 1978 (Box 8)
      Gift of Helen Kowalski, 1978.
  - Portraits
    - Blackwell, ?, undated (Box 8)
    - Blakely, Robert, undated (Box 8)
    - Bryson, Lyman, 1954 (Box 8)
    - Charters, Alexander N., undated; includes photograph of Charters with noted Brazilian educator Paolo Freire (Box 8)
    - Decker, Floyd F., 1928 (Box 8)
    - Diekhoff, John S., 1966 (Box 8)
    - Eisenhower, Dwight David, undated (Box 8)
    - Flemming, Arthur S., 1955 (Box 8)
    - Francis, Clarence and Fletcher C. Scott, undated (Box 8)
    - Freire, Paolo, See Charters, Alexander N.
    - Goldman, Freda, undated (Box 8)
    - Goldwin, Robert A., undated (Box 8)
    - Grattan, C. Harley, undated (Box 8)
    - Hoover, Herbert, undated (Box 8)
    - Houle, Cyril O., undated (Box 8)
    - Kallen, Horace, undated (Box 8)
    - Liveright, A. A., undated (Box 8)
    - McCallion, William, 1960 (Box 8)
    - Nelson, Charles A., undated (Box 8)
    - Norton, Dr. D. Walter, 1943 (Box 8)
    - Osman, John, undated (Box 8)
    - Perkins, Dexter, undated (Box 8)
    - Randall, Clarence B., 1956 (Box 3)
    - Redfield, Robert, undated (Box 8)
    - Scott, Fletcher C., See Francis, Clarence and Fletcher C. Scott.
    - Spengler, Edwin H., undated (Box 8)
    - Stewart, James, undated (Box 8)
    - Tough, Allen, 1983 (Box 8)
    - Truman, Harry S., undated (Box 8)
  - Syracuse University, Syracuse, N.Y.
    - Chautauqua Center -- Film Series, 11 Jul 1964 (Box 8)
    - Commencement, undated (Box 8)
    - Credit management program, undated (Box 8)
    - ERIC/AE, undated (Box 8)
    - Finla Crawford Center for Continuing Education - Dedication, undated (Box 8)
    - Information Resources Seminar, 1975 (Box 8)
    - Publications in Continuing Education -- Conference
      - Minnowbrook, Jun 1971 (Box 9)
      - Sagamore, undated (Box 9)
    - Regional Police Academy dedication, 1971 (Box 9)
    - University College
      - [general], undated (Box 9)
      - Associate in Arts degree, undated (Box 9)
      - ERIC Advisory Group, 1964 (Box 9)
      - Minnowbrook Conferences, 1967-1968; See Slides: Syracuse University, University College: Minnowbrook Conferences
      - Paul Hoy Helms Memorial Collection, 1954 (Box 9)
      - Retirements, undated (Box 9)
      - Thursday morning roundtable - A. Charters, Sam Brightman (Box 9)
      - William Pearson Tolley Award Dinner
        - Award to Dr. Moshan S. Mehta, May 1969 (Box 9)
          See also Slides: Syracuse University, University College: William Pearson Tolley Medal Award 2 - Moshan S. Mehta
        - Lalage Bown, 23 May 1975 (Box 9)
        - Paul Henry Bertelson ?, 11 Apr 1983? (Box 9)
  - UNESCO
    - Regional Seminar, Sydney, Australia, 1964 (Box 9)
    - U.S. National Commission
      - Meeting, Washington, D.C., Oct 1968 (Box 9)
      - Meeting, Washington, D.C., 10 Mar 1969 (Box 9)
    - Workers Education Conference, 1950-1952 (Box 9)
  - University Council on Education for Public Responsibility (UCEPR)
    - University of Oklahoma, 1962 (Box 9)
    - University of Oklahoma (oversize), 1962 (Oversize 1)
  - Victorian Learning and Leisure
    - #1: Mechanics Institutes, undated; packet of historical material, some photos; also includes some printed photographs related to the Workers Education Assocation (England) (Box 9)
      Gift of Derek Legge, 1981.
  - Whittier College, Whittier, Cal.
    - Liberal Arts Center for Adults, undated (Box 9)
  - Wingspread Conference, 1969 (Box 9)
    See also Galaxy Conference
  - Women Trade Unionists
    - Annual Meeting, 1952 (Box 9)
  - Workers Education Assocation, See Victorian Learning and Leisure.
  - World Trade Fair, Milan, Italy
    - U.S. Exhibit, 1955 (Box 9)
  - Unidentified photographs (Box 9)
- Slides
  - Association of University Evening Colleges (AUEC), 1968; regional meeting, R.I.T.; 34 slides (Box 9)
  - Center for the Study of Liberal Education for Adults (CSLEA), educational facilities; 19 slides (Box 9)
  - Indiana Commission on Aging and Aged (ICOAA), Fall 1975; 38 slides (Box 9)
  - National University Extension Association (NUEA), 1968; National Meeting, Miami Beach; 26 slides (Box 9)
  - Syracuse University, University College
    - Minnowbrook Conference, Fall 1967; 6 slides (Box 9)
    - Minnowbrook Conference, 1968; 10 slides (Box 9)
    - William Pearson Tolley Medal Award, Moshan S. Mehta, recipient; 42 slides (Box 9)
- Printed material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 9)